

PERSONAL INFORMATION



19.08.1994



+39 334 5446539



(a) sara.anderlini@hotmail.com



🖔 Bologna, 40122



LANGUAGE **SKILLS**

- Italian (Mother tongue)
- English C1 (iBT TOEFL)
- Spanish B1 (University certificate)
- French B1 (University certificate)

SKILLS

- Driving license, B (selfdriven).
- Coding HTML, CSS, Sass, Bootstrap.
- Versioning Control System - Git.
- Windows Office and Apple Office package.
- Shared repository document collaboration (Outlook, iCloud, Google Drive, etc.).
- Virtual meeting platforms (Teams, Zoom, Google meetings, hangouts, Skype, etc.).
- Captioning tools, Aegisub.
- Cost accounting software, DOS-based.

SARA ANDERLINI

I graduated from the Università di Bologna with a Master's in International Affairs, where I concentrated my studies on security issues and crisis management operations. Over years, I have worked in both for-profit and non-profit, as well as international development sectors, in Italy and abroad.

I am currently studying Front End Web Development, balancing it with my job, focusing on the development of apps and websites.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Accounting Executive Assistant. Comet SpA (Bologna)

05.2021 - Present

- · Administrative secretarial activities management. Prompt handling of internal and external correspondence with suppliers, via phone and email.
- · Recording of passive invoices and payments. Audit and approval of payouts. Making bank transfers and first note registration.

Universal Civil Service at WeWorld-GVC ONLUS (Bologna)

01.2020 - 01.2021

- · Drafting and completion of European projects; coordinator for the implementation and monitoring of ECG programs in the Territory, targeting high school classes and experts.
- Secretary for the XIV edition of the Terra di Tutti Film Festival 2020 (October 6-11, 2020); responsible for the organization of the related events. Correspondence and contact person for liaising with partners, movie-makers, guests.
- · Translation and subtitling (English, Spanish, Italian) of the films selected for screenings. Translation of official documents both for dissemination at national and international level.

LINGUISTIC AND INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCES

Language and Cultural Adaptation Tutor for high school and MBA students.

- · English private classes for students currently enrolled in high schools.
- Italian classes and cultural adaptation tutoring for MBA students from the US.

Group Leader, Study Abroad Coordinator. *Primavera Viaggi* (Florence) 06.2019 - 08.2019

- · Supervisor of the young participants (aged 13-17) in educational trips to Paignton (UK) with regard to relations with host families and boarding school, leading them through all the stages of the journey.
- · Problem solving; organization and planning of activities.

Humanitarian worker. NGO A Drop in the Ocean (Moria Town) and NGO Stitching ShowerPower (Pigadakia), Lesvos, Greece 01.2019 - 03.2019

- Delivering of English lessons for the resident of the camp.
- · Running activities inside and outside the Moria Refugee Camp. Management of relations with local actors and residents of the camp. Reach-out activities on the premises and local towns.

Student Exchange Program at Tapiolan Lukio, Espoo, Finland. 2011-2012 Annual program during the IV year of high school with AFS Intercultura Onlus.

SARA ANDERLINI

SOFT SKILLS

- Flexibility.
- Versatility.
- Accuracy.
- Precision.
- Problem solving.
- Passion for human welfare.
- Ability to work in team and independently, gained at Restaurant II Giardino (Budrio, BO) where I had worked as a waitress for 7 years, during my academic studies.
- Relational skills.
- Strong inclination toward contact with the public.
- Passionate about others.
- Reliability and organizational skills.
- Critical thinking.
- Adaptation to diverse cultural and social contexts.

EDUCATION

Start-2-Impact University, Front End Web Development, Master's Program. 2022 - Present

Development of websites and apps through the main languages of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React. Optimization of website through the use of SEO and SEM.

Università di Bologna, Master's Degree in International Affairs. 2017 - 2021

English-delivered curriculum focusing on the critical analysis of political-economic systems, root causes of related tensions and complexities. Final dissertation titled "Aid under Fire: How Militarization and Politicization Have Hampered Fundamental Humanitarian Principles". Graduation grade 109/110.

University of the Aegean, Lesvos, Greece. Erasmus Semester Program. 2018 - 2019

Study of migration flows in the region, from a historical and political perspective, as well as cross-cultural communication.

Università di Bologna, Bachelor Degree in Political, Social, and International Sciences. 2014 - 2017

Final dissertation titled "La ricaduta giuridica dell'energia nucleare, l'evoluzione del Diritto Internazionale alla luce dell'atomica". Graduation grade 105/110.

SEMINARS AND SUMMER SCHOOL

Seminar GoEAThical, financed by the European Commission. 10.2020

Analysis on the close connection interrelation between food supply chain, climate change, and migration.

Seminar on Media Literacy and Activism, promoted by the European project CIAK Migraction. 02.2020

Course on media literacy and media-activism for migration narratives.

Fondazione Golinelli (partner institution of the Università di Bologna), Summer School in Design Thinking. 09.2019

Subject of study is Design Thinking as a process of creative innovation, employed to increase decision-making capabilities in order for them to be effective and profitable.